# CRISTIAN WILGENHOFF

# Summary

Principal Software Engineer specialised in JavaScript/Typescript.

Having worked in the tech industry since late 2010 for several companies from small startups to big corporate ones, I aim to bring diverse experience and add fruitful value in a role where I can take real software development ownership.

I prefer to work on real and exciting products with active involvement from clients alongside a self-driven team from which I can add value and learn from.

#### Information

- Name: Cristian Wilgenhoff
- **Location**: Remote (EU/UK)
- E-mail: cpwilgenhoff@gmail.com
- Website: <a href="http://cwilgenhoff.github.io/">http://cwilgenhoff.github.io/</a>Github: <a href="https://github.com/cwilgenhoff">https://github.com/cwilgenhoff</a>
- **Phone**: (+44) 07493 074226

# Key Skills

- **Languages**: JavaScript/Typescript
- Web Frameworks: Node.js, Nest.js, Express
- Frontend Libraries/Frameworks: React, Redux, Redux Toolkit, GraphQL
- Workflow Orchestration: Temporal
- **Testing Frameworks**: Jest, Mocha, Cypress, Enzyme, Sinon, Chai
- **Databases**: PostgreSQL, Redis, MongoDB, DynamoDB, MariaDB
- CI/CD Tools: Gitlab CI, Github Actions, CircleCI, Jenkins, Travis CI
- **Containerization & Orchestration**: Docker, Kubernetes
- Cloud Platforms: AWS, Kubernetes, Azure, Open Shift
- Infrastructure as Code: Terraform
- Monitoring & Observability: Datadog, Logz.io (ELK Stack)

#### Yum! Brands, Principal Software Engineer (Contract) (UK)

Jul 2022 – Present

- Principal Engineer (Remote US team)
  - Joined Yum! (parent company of PHDV) to support initially the Menu/Store team and then transitioned to the Payments Team where I worked on two major payment provider integrations within their high-performance payment platform needed for expanding into new markets and countries.
- **Technologies**: Node, Typescript, GraphQL, Temporal, PostgreSQL

## Experience

#### Pizza Hut Digital Ventures, Principal Software Engineer (Contract) (UK)

Jun 2019 – Jul 2022

- Principal Engineer (Remote UK team)
  - Help lead a global vision on re-platforming PHDV systems across all markets. Focused mostly on re-architecting the Menu domain but actively involvSed in the big picture.
- Technical Lead (Remote UK team)
  - o Lead team responsible for supporting, maintaining, and diligently developing new features and A/B testing for markets where PHDV UK had a presence.
- Senior Software Engineer:
  - o Part of a market activation team which brought a new market into an existent event-based platform which was extended to accommodate this new market.
- **Technologies**: React, Node, Nest.JS, Typescript, AWS

## ENGINE | Transformation, Senior Software Engineer (Contract) (UK)

Feb 2019 – Jun 2019

- Part of the development team in charge of developing a product for the UK government (Marine).
  - **Technologies**: React, Node, Typescript, Spring Boot, Azure

#### Red Badger, Senior Software Engineer (UK)

Jun 2017 – Feb 2019

- Part of a consulting team helping mayor high street banks in UK to deliver several products:
  - Authentication Hub (POC): 2-factor biometric authentication for mobile banking applications.
  - o International Payments: Re-vamp of online banking international payments.
  - o Open Banking (Corporate Customer Base): UK government bank regulation.
    - Various tasks ranged from creating an initial structure and development of features for the frontend to the creation/modification of a vast range of microservices with different capabilities such as connectivity to different LDAP servers, DB2 databases and fraud systems along with the creation of pipelines and infrastructure.
  - o Credit Cards App (Retail): Allows retail customers to apply for credit cards.
    - Single Page App with server-side rending. Layered microservices architecture.
       Node Gateway.
- Continuously cultivate the relationship and skillset of the client.
- Technologies: React, Node, Typescript, Spring Boot, Swift, Open Shift, IBM API Connect and Jenkins.

#### FarmDrop, Software Engineer (UK)

March 2016 - Jun 2017

- Part of the customer facing team in charge of building a marketplace for locally sourced food.
- Tasks included adding features fast, migrating legacy Angular components into React, major rebrandings of the shop and several improvements of the current code base through the introduction of standard best practices such as a testing infrastructure for the front-end components using tools like Enzyme. Server-side rendering from a node server.
- **Technologies**: JS (ES6), React, Redux, Node, Webpack, Jest, Enzyme, Ruby on Rails, Redis.

#### Contentment, Software Engineer (UK)

Nov 2015 – Feb 2016

- Part of the development team in charge of building a Reader app; a Cordova application built
  entirely in React acting as a proxy for downloading magazine publications from AWS.
- Worked designing the structure of the app from scratch in a way to load content dynamically.
- Technologies: JS (ES6), React, Node, RxJS, PouchDB.

# Making Sense LLC, Software Engineer (AR)

2012 –2013 & May 2014 – Nov 2015

- Contractor for Centage and Mobiguity Inc Software Engineer
  - o **Technologies**: Javascript, Node, Express, Angular, MongoDB
- Contractor for Best Buy, Easy Soft USA, Migration Mobi Software Engineer
  - o **Technologies**: Dojo Toolkit, JavaScript

#### Globant, Software Engineer (AR)

2011 – 2014

Contractor for Bally Technologies and Deloitte - Software Engineer

#### Southworks, SharePoint Developer (AR)

2010 - 2011

Contractor for Microsoft and KEXP Radio - SharePoint Developer

#### Education

2006 - 2014

# Systems Engineering

National University of Central Buenos Aires (UNICEN) - Buenos Aires, Argentina